

# Varvara Lazarenko

**Address** Nijmegen, The Netherlands

Telephone +31 6 2662 9839 **E-mail** varlazoa@gmail.com Date of birth 29.12.1998 (26 years)

> LinkedIn www.linkedin.com/in/varvara-lazo

#### PERSONAL STATEMENT

I am a curious and dedicated graduate with a Master's degree in Medical Biology, driven by a genuine passion for advancing healthcare through science. My experience spans both fundamental research and clinical trial development. With a solid biomedical background and a keen interest in sharing knowledge, I am motivated to grow within the clinical, MedTech, pharmaceutical, or academic field.

#### **EDUCATION**

# 09/2022 - 08/2024 MSc in Medical Biology - Radboud University, Nijmegen, The Netherlands

- ✓ Specialisation: Science, Management and Innovation
- √ GPA result: 7.63/10.00
- ✓ <u>Principal subjects</u>: Future of health, How Health Systems Work, Sustainable Innovation Management, Molecular and Cellular Neurobiology, Molecular Therapy, Trends in Stem Cell Biology
- ✓ Master thesis: «Potential added value of home telemonitoring technology in elderly care», GPA result: 8.00/10.00

### 09/2016 - 06/2020 BSc in Biology - Lomonosov Moscow State University (MSU), Moscow, Russia

- ✓ <u>Specialisation</u>: Human and Animal Physiology
- √ GPA result: 4.83/5.00
- ✓ <u>Principal subjects</u>: Human and animal physiology, Electrophysiology of excited cells, Physiology of central nervous and visceral systems, Physiology of circulation, Embryology, Genetics, Microbiology, Biochemistry, Immunology
- ✓ <u>Skills</u>: PCR, qPCR, RT-PCR, gel electrophoresis, wire myography, western blotting, ELISA, microscopy, cell culture, immunohistochemistry, intracellular recording (microelectrodes, patch clamp), behaviour tests (open field test, elevated plus maze, light-dark box test)
- ✓ <u>Bachelor thesis</u>: «Role of TASK-1 channels in arterial tone regulation in different organs in rats», GPA result: **5.00/5.00**

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

### 10/2024 - current

# Part-time staff while searching for a life sciences position Renato's Pizzeria - Nijmegen, The Netherlands

- ✓ Providing customer service
- √ Selling the restaurant's menu

#### 02/2024 - 08/2024

#### **Intern at Digital Transformation of Rehabilitation Care**

# HAN University of Applied Sciences - Nijmegen, The Netherlands

- ✓ Added value research of home telemonitoring in elderly care based on the HTA framework presented onto the Quadruple aim
- ✓ Deployment of surveys (22) in Dutch and interviewing (7) medical professionals in English on their home telemonitoring experience/attitude
- √ Cost-effectiveness analysis (Markov model cohort simulation) on home telemonitoring in the Netherlands

#### 02/2023 - 08/2023

# **Intern at Neuronal Networks of Memory**

# **Donders Institute - Nijmegen, The Netherlands**

- ✓ In vivo Ca<sup>2+</sup> imaging of the retrosplenial cortex in mice during head-fixed virtual social learning using two-photon microscopy
- ✓ Management of laboratory animals (GCaMP6 transgenic mice, handling & feeding, craniotomy)
- ✓ Computational analysis of the obtained data (Python, DeepLabCut)

#### 08/2021 - 08/2022 Assistant at the Science Department of the Contract Research Organization

#### LABMGMU, LLC - Moscow, Russia

- ✓ Developing designs, synopses, protocols, investigator's brochures for >35 phase I, II, III clinical trials and bioequivalence trials
- √ >30 user interviews (testing the readability of pharmaceuticals' package leaflets)
- ✓ Advising on the number & design of (pre-)clinical studies for pharma clients
- ✓ Project management (control of the deadlines; compliance with the sponsor's requirements)
- ✓ Computational analysis of the obtained data (STATISTICA, GraphPad Prism)

### 10/2020 – 10/2021 Junior Research Assistant at Faculty of Biology

# Lomonosov Moscow State University - Moscow, Russia

- ✓ Physiological (wire myography technique, rat coronary and renal arteries) and molecular (RNA extraction, reverse transcription, qPCR) experiments
- √ Management of laboratory animals (Wistar rats: housing, care, breeding)
- ✓ Statistical analysis of the obtained data (STATISTICA, GraphPad Prism)
- ✓ Project management (experiment and research strategy planning)
- ✓ Presentation of the results at the <u>virtual conference ARTERY20</u>, 23-24 October 2020, and at the 28th International Scientific Conference "Lomonosov-2021", 12-23 April 2021

#### **DIGITAL SKILLS**

Python (beginner), DeepLabCut, STATISTICA, GraphPad Prism, Rotor-Gene Q Series, and MS Office softwares

#### **LANGUAGES**

Russian (native), English (fluent –  $C_2$ ), German (intermediate –  $B_1$ - $B_2$ ), Dutch (low intermediate –  $A_2$ - $B_1$ ), French (beginner -  $A_1$ )

#### **CERTIFICATES**

2023	A FELASA accredited course on Laboratory Animal Science (EU function B) at Radboudumc
2021	An upgrade training on ICH guidelines on Good Clinical Practice (GCP) at LABMGMU

#### **ACADEMIC HONORS AND AWARDS**

VOLUNTEERING ACTIVITY		
2021	Second prize-winner in the Lomonosov Universiade on modern problems of biology	
2020-2021	Awarded MSU Increased State Academic Scholarship for scientific and academic achievements	
2022-2024	Awarded Orange Tulip Scholarship for the studies at Radboud University	

2024	Mentorship of the international exchange and Master's students at the Radboud Intro
2023	Organization of the BBB Career Event 2023, Nijmegen
2022-2023	Organization of volleyball tournaments in the international volleyball group at Radboud
2018-2021	Mentorship of the first-year students at Faculty of Biology, MSU, Moscow

#### **HOBBIES**

Animals (horses & dogs), volleyball, reading, drawing, guitar playing, traveling

#### SCIENTIFIC JOURNAL PUBLICATIONS

- 1. Shvetsova Anastasia A., **Lazarenko Varvara S.**, Gaynullina Dina K., Tarasova Olga S., Schubert Rudolf (2022). TWIK-Related Acid-Sensitive Potassium Channels (TASK-1) Emerge as Contributors to Tone Regulation in Renal Arteries at Alkaline pH. *Frontiers in physiology*, *13*: 895863. https://doi.org/10.3389/fphys.2022.895863
- **2. Lazarenko Varvara**, Shvetsova Anastasia, Gaynullina Dina, Schubert Rudolph (2020). TASK-1 Channels Play an Anticontractile Role in Rat Septal Coronary Artery Under Pharmacological Blockade of Endothelium. *Artery Research*, *26*(S1): S58. <a href="https://doi.org/10.2991/artres.k.201209.048">https://doi.org/10.2991/artres.k.201209.048</a>
- 3. Borzykh A.A., Kuzmin I.V., Kiryukhina O.O., Selivanova E.K., Shvetsova A.A., **Lazarenko V.S.**, Los-Arkos Uvarova S., Nesterenko A.M., Tarasova O.S. (2020). Voluntary running training of female rats during gestation: characteristics of an experimental model [in Russian]. *Aviakosmicheskaya i Ekologicheskaya Meditsina*, *54*(2): 89–95. <a href="https://www.elibrary.ru/item.asp?id=42721639">https://www.elibrary.ru/item.asp?id=42721639</a>